

# Rohit Sharma

Rooms Division Manager

rohitsharma009@outlook.com

+971 55 152 7399

rohit.sharma009

.\_ . . . . . . . . . . .

Kappa Acca2, #1315, Dubailand, Dubai Q

I'm a MBA in Tourism & Hospitality Management with over 14 years of hands on rooms operations that includes an exposure in Business, Leisure, pre-opening, Resorts, Hotels & Apartments. Efficiently manages the operations, recognized for outstanding organizational skills, creativity, public relations and an ability to consistently exceed guest expectations. Ability of providing training on value-added customer service & achieving desired results by providing customized training as per requirements. Possess an adaptable, flexible approach to work and good inter-personal skills.

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## • Rooms Division Manager

Novotel Bur Dubai

10/2021 - Present

A franchised Accor hotel with 219 rooms, 4 F&B outlets,2 meeting rooms, spa, gym, swimming pool

## **Output** Cluster Front Office Manager

Pullman Dubai Creek City Centre Hotel & Residences

04/2019 - 09/2021

A combo of hotel & residences with a total of 450 keys, 5 F&B outlets, 11 meeting rooms, spa, gym, swimming pool, executive lounge.

## **Operation** Complex Front Office Manager

Novotel & Ibis Gate Hotel Abu Dhabi

09/2016 – 03/2019 Accor group of hotels, this is a combo property with 518 keys, 8 F&B outlets, 7 meeting rooms, swimming pool, spa, gym.

# • Assistant Front Office Manager

Novotel & Ibis Gate Hotel Abu Dhabi

03/2015-08/2016 Accor group of hotels, this is a combo property with 518 keys, 8 F&B outlets, 7 meeting rooms, swimming pool, spa, gym.

#### Assistant Manager Welcomer

Pullman Gurgaon Central Park (Pre-Opening)

12/2011 – 01/2015 1st Pullman in India, an upscale brand near to the airport with 285 keys. Now known as Le Meridien.

#### Assistant Manager Front Office

Radisson Blu Resort & Spa Alibaug, Mumbai

07/2010 – 12/2011 A great wedding destination with 156 keys with 6 F&B outlets, 4 meetings rooms, library, meditation room, games room.

#### Management Associate

Radisson Hotel Varanasi

06/2009 – 06/2010 Carlson Group of Hotels. A good mix of business & leisure guests with a total of 116 keys.

### **EDUCATION**

O MBA

Hospitality & Tourism Management

2012 – 2013 UBI, Brussels- Belgium

# O Bachelor in Hotel Management & Catering

Technology

2005 – 2009 Jaipur National University, Jaipur- India

Senior Secondary/High School

Dayanand Public School, Shimla- India

### COMPUTER SKILLS

Opera

Micros

Triton

Microsoft Office- Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook

Hot Sos

Shawman

Oasvs

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- O Increased the RPS score for Novotel Bur Dubai by 4% for the 2022 as compared to 2021.
- O Successfully got Novotel Bur Dubai in Top 100 hotels over TripAdvisor in Dubai from 177 rank in 2021
- O Controlled the HK manning, laying out a simple worksheet in accordance to the productivity report. Increase in the cleanliness score by 2% each month & raising the level of cleanliness
- O Secured 96% in the BARE audit for 2022 & Rooms Division score was 99% (for both FO & HK)
- O 15% increase from last year in loyalty program enrollments through extensive on job training & monitoring
- The Employee Engagement score was moved to 91 for 2019 as compared to 67 for 2018 for front office
- O Secured 1<sup>st</sup> position in the ALL competition in overall UAE & Egypt in Oct'2018
- O AED 2.4 million upselling incremental revenue for the year 2017 with a raise of almost 1 million as compared to 2016

# **REFERENCES**

Mr. Muhammad Jahanzeb Khan Director Talent & Culture- Pullman JLT & Novotel &

Ibis Abu Dhabi Gate

Mobile- +971 552260475

Email- jahanzeb.khan@accor.com

Mrs. Nicola Hochgruber

**Director- Hotels Operation NCTH** 

Mobile- +971 567481572

Email- nicola@ncth.ae